{"tossups": [{"question": "This man claimed that there is \u201csimply no excuse for the mayhem that followed\u201d the verdict in the Rodney King trial in his speech<em> Reflections on Urban America</em>. During one debate, this man criticized the book<em> Earth in the Balance</em> which had recently been released by his opponent. After claiming that a former President was a friend of his, Lloyd Bentsen told this man \u201cSenator, you\u2019re not Jack Kennedy.\u201dFor ten points, name this Vice President under George H.W. Bush.", "answer": "Dan<b> Quayle</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One artist from this country used floating geometric forms in his non-objective art and founded the Suprematist movement. Another artist used photomontage to show an oversized leader of this country speaking in front of industrial wires and phonograph-like speakers. Emigrants from this country to Munich, Germany founded the Blue Rider movement. A propagandistic \u201cillustration\u201d was created by Varvara Stepanova to represent a Five-Year Plan instituted in, for ten points, what home country of artists Kasimir Malevich and Wassily Kandinsky?", "answer": "<b> Russia</b> (accept<b> Soviet Union</b>; accept<b> USSR</b> or<b> Union of Soviet Socialist Republics</b>; accept<b> CCCP</b> or<b> Soyuz Sovetskikh Sotsialisticheskikh Respublik</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Precedents for this Supreme Court case included<em> Kirby v. Kirby</em> and<em> Kinney v. The Commonwealth</em>. Robert McIlwaine represented the state party in this case using precedents like<em> Naim v. Naim</em> and<em> Pace</em> <em>v. Alabama</em>. The 9-0 ruling in this case held that anti-miscegenation laws violated the Equal Protection and Due Process Clauses. For ten points, name this landmark 1967 case that ended bans on interracial marriage.", "answer": "<b> Loving</b> v. Virginia", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Walter Kauffman\u2019s biography of this man argued that syphilis caused his end of life madness, which seemingly began with an 1889 incident in which he rushed to save a horse from being beaten on the streets of Turin. This thinker, who stated that the \u201cabyss will gaze back into you\u201d in<em> Beyond Good and</em> <em>Evil</em>, discussed the role of the Apollonian and the Dionysian in his<em> The Birth of Tragedy</em>. Nazi German philosophy was heavily influenced by, for ten points, what German author of<em> Thus Spake Zarathustra</em>?", "answer": "Frederich<b> Nietzsche</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "Prior to this battle, Joachim Murat [yoh-ah-keem mu-rah] was admonished for declaring an armistice at Sch\u00a8ongrabern [SCHUN-grah-bern] without his superior\u2019s consent, giving the enemy time to join forces near Brno [BIR-no]. One general, who sought to begin this battle before the entrance of Prussia into the war, baited Franz von Weyrother\u2019s [VIE-roh-ter\u2019s] forces by abandoning the Pratzen Heights. The Treaty of Pressburg was signed after this battle, dissolving the Holy Roman Empire. For ten points, name this 1805 victory over the Third Coalition by Napoleon.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Austerlitz</b> (accept Battle of the<b> Three Emperors</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In the prelude to this conflict, Jeffery Amherst heavily restricted the use of gunpowder. The Conestoga Massacre was carried out by the Paxton Boys in the aftermath of this conflict. Appalled by colonial behavior during this conflict, George III passed a law banning settlers from moving past the Appalachian Mountains. The Royal Proclamation of 1763 was passed in response to, for ten points, what rebellion led by a namesake Ottawa Chief?", "answer": "<b> Pontiac\u2019s</b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This empire was ruled by the Asen Dynasty which came to power after Ivan Asen won a 7-year siege at Tarnovo. Basil II fought a series of wars against this empire, earning a nickname for slaying its people. A leader of this empire had the Peslav Literary School create the Cyrillic alphabet. Under the leadership of Simeon the Great, this empire fought the Magyars in several wars with neighboring Hungary. For ten points, name this empire that, in 809 AD, took control of Sofia.", "answer": "<b> Bulgar</b>ian Empire", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A commission led by Robert La Follette Sr. began investigating this event after the ransacking of the Senate Office Building. The Supreme Court held that Congress had the power to compel testimony in<em> McGrain v. Daugherty</em>, which stemmed from Harry Daugherty\u2019s failure to investigate the perpetrators of this event. During this scandal, Albert Fall leased public land owned by the Navy, such as Elk Hills, to private oil companies. For ten points, name this land scandal during the administration of Warren G. Harding.", "answer": "<b> Teapot Dome</b> scandal", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This author\u2019s<em> How Many Subjects? Statistical Power Analysis in Research</em> studied the social impact of hiding sexual orientation. Mark Judge denied \u201cany memory [...] whatsoever\u201d of a 1982 incident in which he stopped an altercation between this woman and her attacker, who served on the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals until October 2018. For ten points, name this research psychologist from Stanford University who reported being sexually assaulted by Supreme Court justice Brett Kavanaugh.", "answer": "Christine<b> Blasey Ford</b> (accept either or both last names)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "During this conflict, the anarchist Nestor Mahkno seized control of an army due to a power vacuum caused by the fall of Hetman Skoropadsky\u2019s government. Wrangel\u2019s Fleet fled to occupied Constantinople at the end of the \u201csouthern\u201d front of this conflict. American troops occupied Vladivostok during this conflict in support of Alexander Kolchak\u2019s provisional government. For ten points, name this 1917 conflict between the Mensheviks and Bolsheviks for control of a European nation.", "answer": "<b> Russian Civil War</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In 1910, the mayor of this city, J. Barry Mahool, passed an ordinance barring blacks from moving into white majority areas such as the Eutaw Place neighborhood. This city was the site of the Pratt Street Riots where Union soldiers, en route to Camden Station, clashed with secessionists. In an invasion of this city, the British navy bombarded Fort McHenry, an attack that inspired Francis Scott Key to write the\u201cStar-Spangled Banner.\u201d For ten points, name this city which flourished as the busiest port in Maryland.", "answer": "<b> Baltimore</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The \u201cDope Sheet\u201d was a press release that this NFL team\u2019s co-founder wrote in its first few seasons. This team won the 1967 NFL Championship game, which had a game-time temperature of negative 15 degrees and was known as the \u201cIce Bowl.\u201d This team anchors the smallest market for any team in the four major American sports leagues. Vince Lombardi coached, for ten points, what publicly-owned NFL team that plays its home games at Lambeau Field in Wisconsin?", "answer": "<b> Green Bay Packers</b> (accept either underlined portion)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This event led to the dispatch of a riverboat column under Charles Wilson that arrived two days late and a desert column that fought at Abu Klea. Rudolf von Slatin was shown the decapitated head of a general during this event. George W. Joy\u2019s depiction of this event</b> <b>features a man (+)</b> <b>staring at his watch as soldiers run up a set of stairs to spear him.</b> <b>William Gladstone\u2019s nickname changed from G.O.M. to M.O.G. thanks to this event, in which (*) </b> Muhammad Ahmad\u2019s dervishes beheaded Charles Gordon. For ten points, name this 1885 event in which the Mahdists seized Sudan\u2019s capital.", "answer": "Siege/Fall/etc. of<b> Khartoum</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>In this modern-day state, Edmund Fanning and Francis Nash faced corruption charges from a group that fought William Tryon at the Battle of Alamance. The Great Awakening inspired a farmer from this state, Herman Husband, to create the anti-colonial (+) Regulator Movement. The word \u201cCroatoan\u201d inscribed in a tree was allegedly the only clue of what happened to the (*) </b> Roanoke Colony in this state. Charles I inspired the name of, for ten points, what state whose capital is named after Walter Raleigh?", "answer": "<b> North Carolina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A religion that developed in this country exclusively uses oral tradition and syncretizes the Orishas of Yoruban belief with the</b><em><b> vodun</b></em><b> of West Africa. That faith of this country,</b> <em><b>Candombl\u00b4e</b></em><b>, is practiced by the</b><em><b> povo de santo</b></em><b> and incorporates aspects of (+)</b> <em><b>Candombl\u00b4e</b></em><b>, is practiced by the</b><em><b> povo de santo</b></em><b> and incorporates aspects of (+)</b> <b>Roman</b> <b>Catholicism, this country\u2019s majority religion. A 100-foot-tall (*)</b> statue of Christ overlooks a statue of Christ overlooks a city in this country that hosts the world\u2019s largest pre-Lenten Carnival. For ten points, name this country where the Cristo Redentor statue stands in Rio de Janeiro.", "answer": "<b> Brazil</b>", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Soldiers on the losing side at this battle were given until the 25th of August to surrender in exchange for a full pardon. The Duke of Schomberg was among the leaders of the winning</b> <b>side killed at this battle, which was followed by the Declaration of (+)</b> <b>Finglas. One side</b> <b>Finglas. One side</b> <b>fled to Limerick following this battle, where they successfully fended off a siege. (*)</b> <b>fled to Limerick following this battle, where they successfully fended off a siege. (*)</b> Dutch Blue Guards were employed by the winning side of this battle fought near a namesake river. For ten points, name this 1690 victory for William of Orange, after which James II fled the British Isles.", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Boyne</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "(+) Jan Palach protested the end of this period</b> <b>by setting himself ablaze in Wenceslas Square. The (*)</b> Brezhnev doctrine was invoked to end this period through overwhelming military force. For ten points, name this 1968 period in which \u201csocialism with a human face\u201d was implemented in Czechoslovakia.", "answer": "<b> Prague Spring </b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}